<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shavi Hewage</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shavi Hewage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Column 1 ???
 Some text..
 Column 2 Some text..
  Contact Info   lijia.yu@outlook.com  github.com/yulijia  +1 000-000-0000 For more information, please contact me via email.   Skills  Experienced in statistical analysis, statistical learning models, and optimization methods.
 Full experience with next generation sequencing data analysis.
 Highly skilled in R, Bash, Perl, Python, LaTeX
   Main Lijia Yu Currently searching for a PhD student position Please note that this is a real resume, and I’m really looking for a PhD student position at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R and Python Together</title>
      <link>/blog/r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Why Would Anyone Need To Do This? Have you ever had the urge to do things in two languages at the same time? It’s literally code-switching. When you’re at home and you’re talking to your mom or maybe your grandma, and you unwittingly switch between your home language and English?
Your mom: තේ බොමු ද?
You: Sure! Do we have any කිඹුල් බනිස්?
(maybe this is not a universal experience, but it is a common experience for a good chunk of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
  Project 1
  Project 2
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/eda/</guid>
      <description>🇨🇦 Introduction 🇺🇸 In recent years, the YouTube Trending page has been one of the more controversial topics amongst users of the site. This is mostly because the manner in which videos appear on the Trending page is a mystery (in 2018, for example, the website Polygon wrote an article about the controversy surrounding offensive videos surfacing on this page).
I chose this particular dataset because I spend a lot of time on YouTube, and I was curious to see how Trending videos differ by country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling</title>
      <link>/modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/modeling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This dataset is a fun amalgmation of a bunch of different state-level health data from 2017. We’re going to use this to look at differences between Democratic and Republican states in terms of their healthcare, and then go the other way and predict which states are Democrat or Republican affiliated based on their healthcare statistics.
Variables include:
State, affiliation during 2016 election (source), population (source), antibiotic prescription rate per thousand (source), opioid prescription rate per thousand (source), total payments from drug companies accepted by doctors per state (source), drug deaths per 100,000 population (source), and public health funding per person (source).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>